[instrumental music]
[suspenseful music]
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
[music continues]
[water gushing]
I think I can see something.
What?
What is it?
- Boo!
- Ah!
Selah!
[both laugh]
I knew you were making it up!
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[bird chirps]
[birds chirping]
[sheep bleats]
♪ Oh don't you remember ♪
♪ A long time ago ♪
♪ Those two little babes ♪
♪ Their names I don't know ♪
♪ They strayed away ♪
♪ One bright summer's day ♪
♪ Those two little babes ♪
♪ Got lost on their way ♪
♪ Pretty babes in the wood ♪
♪ Oh don't you remember ♪
♪ Those babes in the wood.. ♪
[indistinct chatter]
Look, we gotta save it.
Uh..
[chuckles]
[wind whooshing]
[instrumental music]
[laughter]
[indistinct chatter]
- Would anyone like more lamb?
- Hm, that's..
Are you guys good down there?
Yeah?
Yeah, I can tell.
Someone keeps stealing my knife.
[claps]
Wives.
Daughters.
Thank you.
[instrumental music]
Do you accept my grace?
I do, Shepherd.
[door opens]
[doorknob rattles]
[door creaks]
Oh, my Shepherd.
I need you.
Come, and help me.
I need a deeper experience
with you
than I have ever had before.
Come down upon me,
and fill me with yourself.
Help me be closer to you.
Thank you, Shepherd, for
allowing us to be your wives.
Thank you for your grace
and love.
Thank you for a beautiful day.
[crickets chirping]
[bird caws]
[sheep bleats]
Thank you.
[bird caws]
[sheep bleats]
Thank you.
Have we truly
stripped ourselves
from the knowledge
that keeps us
from the grace of Eden?
- Yes, Shepherd.
- Yes Shepherd?
Do we seek that experience?
We seek a profound experience..
Have we cleansed ourselves
from the rot
of the outside world?
Yes, Shepherd.
- Have we?
- Yes, my Shepherd.
My wives.
You all came to me..
...broken..
...searching..
...hurt by a cruel world
that is more filled
with pain every day.
I took every one of you in.
I protected you.
I sacrificed my life for you.
I gave you shelter
I gave you daughters
and sisterhood..
...and life.
[deep breathing]
[sighs]
Let us pray.
And reflect on our blessings.
Oh, my Shepherd,
we seek a profound experience.
[overlapping chatter]
Oh, my Shepherd, come down upon
me and fill me with yourself..
[overlapping chatter]
Oh, my Shepherd..
[screaming]
[ominous music]
[wind whooshing]
Tamar, should you see
if Maria needs help?
Of course.
See you later, Selah.
Did you like my sermon, Selah?
I'm glad.
I can always tell
when my sermons are boring
for your gaze wanders up
amongst the trees.
My Shepherd, no, your sermons
are always wonderful.
I'm only teasing.
[chuckles]
I know you listen most ardently.
[instrumental music]
So beautiful.
Just like your mother.
Can you tell me the story
of when you first saw her again?
So beautiful.
Can you tell me the story again?
When you first saw her?
[music continues]
Make sure one of the wives
re-braids your hair.
He looked at me.
And then..
I mean..
I'd never felt
anything like that before.
Shepherd just said
"Shall I hold you?"
That's how it is
being a wife.
It is like healing, sisters.
And he just kept telling me
"You are perfect"
and "You are accepted."
And then he held me there
in his arms.
In that moment,
everything was perfect
and I knew I never wanted
to leave.
"You are perfect"
"You are accepted."
You only just came here.
Selah!
You can't. She's a wife.
She's the same age as us,
though.
You're not allowed to speak
to a wife like that.
I'll tell on you.
Sheep-shit you will!
Sisters. Stop!
Mommy!
Selah hit me.
Selah.
Have you anything to say?
She started being
mean to Eloise
even though she's a wife
and Shepherd says
we're not meant to be mean..
Tattle-tale.
- What was that, Selah?
- Nothing.
If you two sisters
cannot work together
then I suppose
I'm gonna have to separate you.
Selah, take the leftovers
out to the hut please.
[quacking]
[yells]
[instrumental music]
[flies buzzing]
[panting]
What are you doing,
you stupid child?
Give it to me.
The offerings are rich today
I see.
You know the food
is meant as penance.
To help purify.
She won't eat.
She's fasting.
She thinks the bleeding
is punishment for Eve's sin.
She's right,
the Shepherd says so.
You think that because
you haven't had your time yet
that makes you special.
He tells you that.
But it will come soon enough.
Prepare yourself, child.
Our great Shepherd
won't be so sweet on you then.
If you are impure, is it not
right to drive out the rot?
[laughs]
So pious and perfect.
Just like your mother was.
Don't touch me!
You are unclean.
You can leave now, little one.
I'll be seeing you
when the blood comes to you.
Get out.
[water gurgling]
[laughing]
Okay. Come on, girls.
Shh-shh-shh. Come on.
Time for bed. Come on, Lily.
Come on, come up here.
But, mama, I'm not tired.
I know, but you have to
go to sleep now, Lily.
You know the rules.
But I want a story.
Stories can only be told about
the flock and the shepherd.
And only the shepherd
is allowed to tell them.
Okay? You know that.
You don't wanna get Selah
in trouble now, do you?
- No.
- I'm sorry, Selah.
- Okay.
- It's okay, Lily.
I know you didn't mean it.
Okay.
So mama's gotta go, okay?
But Selah's gonna stay with you
and then you're
gonna go to sleep.
[crickets chirping]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
Shepherd,
the lambs will be coming soon.
That was your last food
and drink.
We mustn't contaminate the
newborn lambs with impurities.
You are too young
for such a responsibility.
But if the Shepherd wills it.
You have witnessed a birth
of one of your sisters before?
It's like that.
When the ewe is ready, she lays
down in the birthing position
ready to help the lamb arrive.
It's the most natural thing
in the world, Selah.
And the most sacred duty.
The Shepherd
is trusting you greatly.
[sheep bleating]
[instrumental music]
[wind whooshing]
[sheep bleating]
[instrumental music]
[breathing heavily]
[intense music]
[screaming]
[instrumental music]
[bird calling]
[birds calling]
Selah?
What happened with the lambs?
The wives wouldn't tell me
anything.
Just that you were
with the Shepherd.
Selah, what happened?
I fell asleep.
A wild dog got one of the lambs.
Killed it.
Selah?
[grunting]
[screams]
And when the wives found out,
they went and got Shepherd
and Maria took me to the church.
Shh.
He forgave me.
But it is worse than punishment.
I didn't believe hard enough
in the flock, in the Shepherd.
I was impure.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[ram breathing heavily]
[raven cawing]
[engine rumbling]
[door opens]
[indistinct radio chatter]
[chattering on radio]
[indistinct chatter]
You're gonna have to leave.
If I don't,
will you arrest me?
You've got a few days.
[indistinct chatter]
[engine rumbling]
[breathing heavily]
[footsteps approaching]
[instrumental music]
My precious flock.
I have grievous news.
To protect us all,
we must leave.
Otherwise, the outside world
will destroy us
and take you all away from me.
[thudding]
We will find a new home.
[laughing]
[instrumental music]
♪ It's the last goodbye
I swear ♪
♪ I can't rely ♪
♪ On a dime a day love ♪
♪ That don't go anywhere ♪
♪ I learn to cry
for someone else ♪
♪ I can't get by ♪
♪ On an odds and ends love ♪
♪ That don't ever match up ♪
♪ I heard all you said ♪
♪ And I took it to heart ♪
♪ I won't forget I swear ♪
♪ I have no regrets ♪
♪ For the past is behind me ♪
♪ Tomorrow reminds me
just where ♪
[music continues]
[birds calling]
So we can never come back?
We have to find a new place.
Just like we found this one,
years ago.
I am relying on you, Selah.
Of all my children,
you're the purest in your faith.
The younger sisters
will look to you for guidance.
Be strong.
[bird cawing]
My dear flock.
Our path will be long,
and arduous.
But with faith, we will find
our way to rebirth.
♪ Oh don't you remember
a long time ago? ♪
♪ Those two little babes ♪
♪ Their names I don't know ♪
♪ They strayed away
one bright summer's day ♪
♪ Those two little babes ♪
♪ Got lost on their way ♪
♪ Pretty babes in the wood ♪
[instrumental music]
[gnawing]
[snarling]
For our journey
we give thanks.
And with this flesh,
we shall be reborn.
- We shall be reborn.
[fire crackling]
[gasps]
[crickets chirping]
[instrumental music]
[intense music]
[wind howling]
[flies buzzing]
[water dripping]
[instrumental music]
I told you not to go in here.
Why can't we set up in here?
It's warmer.
This is a broken place..
...made by broken people.
Get out.
[crickets chirping]
[urinating]
♪ There were two sisters
walking down the street ♪
♪ Oh the wind and the rain ♪
♪ Then they're able to walk ♪
♪ Through the dark all day ♪
♪ Of the dreadful
wind and rain ♪
♪ People had a love ♪
♪ Of a Shepherd's grace ♪
♪ Oh the wind and the rain ♪
[instrumental music]
[gasping]
[exhaling]
[Selah retching]
[Selah coughing]
[breathing heavily]
[screaming]
She is impure!
[dramatic music]
[wind howling]
Mm.
Do you remember when he used to
look at us like that?
When we had all of his grace.
It's different now
because you're old.
What happened to you?
He said it was punishment..
...for my vanity.
He said the same
when he cut my hair.
Now he calls me a broken thing.
I don't believe you.
You look so much like your
mother when you say that.
What was she like?
She was beautiful, of course.
We joined the flock
at the same time.
We were the first
to be given his grace.
His attention is like the sun.
It's bright and glorious
at first.
But then it just..
...burns.
I don't know
why you would say that.
Of course you don't.
Not yet.
I was jealous of your mother
at first.
You must have been glad
when she died then.
Having me.
That's what you think, child?
She was fine for days
after you were born.
But then there was an infection.
He said it was a test
of her faith.
He didn't take her
to the hospital.
[instrumental music]
♪ I let you down ♪
♪ I know two times in a row ♪
♪ A sign ♪
♪ Beside ♪
♪ A wall ♪
♪ We could ♪
♪ Not climb ♪
♪ I let you.. ♪
[instrumental music]
[inaudible]
[wind howling]
[instrumental music]
[fire crackling]
[crickets chirping]
You know you can't stay here
with me forever.
He counts the days.
He knows our private rhythms.
But I still don't feel right.
Sometimes..
...when I was still
a favored wife
I would get this restlessness
under my skin.
And I would wait until it was
dark and everything was quiet.
I would go out into the woods.
I would take off my robes..
...and just be.
It felt like freedom.
Why do you stay?
[sighs]
Because..
...I'm afraid.
I've been here for so long.
I don't even know
who I am anymore.
[creaking]
[deep breathing]
[retches]
[wind howling]
You were away for so long.
My bleed was only short
the first time.
And with the cursed-wife,
what does she speak of?
She doesn't say much.
It's her penance.
Shepherd says
it's to atone for her sin.
Well, it must be,
if the Shepherd says so.
[instrumental music]
Sorry you had to leave us.
She's a broken thing.
[panting]
[groaning]
[sobbing]
Is it time?
No, no, it can't be time.
It can be not.
It's too soon. It's too soon.
I can't do this here.
Breathe! Breathe.
- I can't do this here.
- Breathe.
I can't do this here.
Please. No.
[groaning]
I can't. I can't do this here.
I can't.
- You can.
- No, I can't.
- Not now.
- It won't be now.
- I can't do this here.
- Shepherd!
- It's okay.
It's okay. Just breathe.
Just breathe.
- It's gonna be alright.
- It's okay. It's okay.
Shepherd!
[groaning]
[Adriel screams]
Push!
[sobbing]
[Adriel screams]
Push.
Come on. Come on.
- Push!
- Okay.
[baby crying]
[sobbing]
Get down.
No.
[sobbing]
- Get down! Come!
- No. Mommy, mommy!
- Get down.
- Mommy! Mommy.
[sighs]
This happened because of you..
...Michael.
Maria.
[fire crackling]
[wind howling]
♪ As I went down
in the valley to pray ♪
♪ Studying about that
good ol' way ♪
♪ And who shall wear
the starry crown ♪
♪ Good Lord show me the way ♪
♪ Oh sisters let's go down ♪
♪ Let's go down come on down ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh sisters let's go down ♪
♪ Down in the valley to pray ♪
♪ As I went down
in the valley to pray ♪
♪ Studying about that
good ol' way ♪
♪ And who shall wear
the starry crown ♪
♪ Good Lord show me the way! ♪
♪ The way! ♪
♪ Oh mourners let's go down ♪
♪ Let's go down ♪
♪ Let's go down come on down ♪
♪ Oh mourners let's go down ♪
♪ Down ♪
♪ Down in the valley to pray ♪
♪ To pray ♪
[fire crackling]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
Why aren't you coming with us?
He wanted to leave the baby.
He said it should be with
its mother's ashes.
The baby?
But I thought
it was born wrong.
He's perfect.
[crying]
It's a boy?
Only one ram in a flock, child.
You are so strong.
Promise me you'll remember that.
And help your sisters
to remember too.
[instrumental music]
Shepherd, are we nearly there?
[wind howling]
I think I see something...
that way.
Tamar... would you like
to lead us?
No, Shepherd.
I just..
Walk.
- Ah!
- Walk!
Get up and show us! Walk!
[Tamar groans]
Tamar, walk, walk!
[groans]
[sobs]
Go.
Please.
Walk!
[sobbing]
Pathetic.
You can't be mine.
[sobbing]
[instrumental music]
We must have faith.
[Tamar sobs]
[music continues]
He shouldn't have done that
to you.
[music continues]
My dear faithful flock!
As a reward
for your faith in me
I give you paradise on earth.
Eden.
[wind howling]
[serene music]
You must release yourself,
your earthly worries
and trust in me to hold you,
to save you
to give you my grace.
[water splashes]
[gasping]
[splash]
You must release yourself,
your earthly worries
and trust in me to hold you,
to save you
to give you my grace.
[splash]
[gasping]
I feel different.
[splash]
[gasping]
[gasps]
[instrumental music]
[screams]
[gasping]
Mother, your hair
is so beautiful.
Would you like some?
No thank you, Tamar.
We are fasting.
Tomorrow, we wives
will be reborn.
This is Eden.
It has to be.
[footsteps approaching]
Selah.
Come.
Don't go, Selah.
Don't go.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
Unbraid your hair.
Come here.
[footsteps approaching]
You're so beautiful.
Just like your mother.
Lie down.
[instrumental music]
I remember when I first
saw your mother.
[music continues]
[gasps]
Shh.
[breathing heavily]
Goodnight, my sweet Selah.
[suspenseful music]
[fire crackling]
[music continues]
I'm going to tell you a story.
Selah, only the Shepherd
can tell the stories.
There once was a woman.
A wild woman.
Made of moonlight and teeth.
And sometimes,
she would roam in the woods
searching for something.
Hunting.
And the wind, and the trees
and the water
would speak to her.
Talk to her and tell her tales.
Tell her where to go.
Tell her to be free.
[instrumental music]
Sisters..
...the wives are gone.
There has been a miracle.
The sacred lake of rebirth
has given the wives
the grace of eternal life.
They found the way back home.
Where's my mother?
[sobs]
Daughters, this was the path
I had to take..
...for you sisters
to become the wives.
Selah. My sweet Selah.
My beautiful Selah.
My wife.
Come here.
I will take you
in my arms, Selah
and I will give you my grace.
Come here.
I'll give you my grace.
You are not our shepherd.
I don't want your grace.
[instrumental music]
[heavy breathing]
[suspenseful music]
[intense music]
[grass rustling]
Well, this is fucked.
[camera shutter clicks]
[birds chirping]
[instrumental music]
[bleats]
♪ Oh don't you remember
a long time ago? ♪
♪ Those two little babes
their names I don't know ♪
♪ They strayed away
one bright summer's day ♪
♪ Those two little babes ♪
♪ Got lost on their way ♪
♪ Pretty babes in the wood ♪
♪ Oh don't you remember
those babes in the wood? ♪
♪ Now the day being gone ♪
♪ And the night coming on ♪
♪ Those two little babes
lay under a stone ♪
♪ They wept and they cried ♪
♪ They sobbed and they sighed ♪
♪ Those two little babes ♪
♪ They laid down and died ♪
[instrumental music]
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
[music continues]